enchroma.com 2019-09-23

# Privacy | EnChroma® Color Blind Glasses

EnChroma, Inc. (“EnChroma” or “we” or “our” or “us”) respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. This Privacy Policy describes the types of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit, interact with, or use our website [www.enchroma.com](http://www.enchroma.com/), and any of our microsites, mobile sites, mobile applications, or SMS or email notifications (collectively, the “Websites”), and our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, and disclosing that information.

This Privacy Policy does not cover any information EnChroma collects or maintains offline, unless specifically stated otherwise. This privacy policy describes:

  * The kind of information we collect about you;
  * Why we collect this information;
  * How we use this information;
  * When and with whom we share the information;
  * How we protect the information; and
  * Your choices with respect to such information.

Please read this policy carefully. By accessing and using the Websites, you agree to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy may change from time to time (see “ **What if there are changes to this Privacy Policy or if I have questions about it?”** ), please check this Privacy Policy periodically for updates. Your continued use of the Websites after we make changes is deemed to be acceptance of those changes.

## **What information does EnChroma collect about me and why?**

EnChroma collects personal and other information that you directly provide to us when you use our Websites, fill in a form, post materials, or make purchases, including, but not limited to, your name, e-mail address, phone number, and shipping and billing addresses (“personal information”). We also collect records of your correspondence if you contact us.

The businesses of EnChroma and our Websites are not designed for children. EnChroma does not knowingly collect any personal information from or about a child under the age of 13 years.

If you provide information to be published or displayed on public areas of the Websites, such as writing a review through EnChroma’s review functionality, or if you provide information to be transmitted to other users of the Websites or third parties, such information is posted or transmitted at your own risk and may be viewed by others. We cannot control and are not responsible for actions of other visitors, users, or third parties with whom you may share information.

We also collect information automatically as you browse or navigate our Websites. This information may include such information as usage details, domain names, access times and referring website addresses, browsing patterns, IP addresses, geolocation, and information about your internet connection or the equipment or device you use to access our Websites. We collect this information to learn about how people use our Websites, to improve your online experience with our Websites, and to offer goods and services that may be of interest to you. We may collect this type of usage and preference information through the use of cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies that create and maintain unique identifiers. We may also tie usage and preference information to other information you provide to us.

A cookie is a piece of data that a website sends to a visitor’s computer or mobile device, which that device’s browser transmits back to the website on subsequent visits. A cookie may assign a unique identification code to your device, so that our website is able  to provide you with a personalized browsing experience.

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your device’s internet browser. In order to disable cookies, please consult your device’s or browser’s configuration functions or help section for instructions. If you turn off cookies, however, you may not be able to use some of the features of our Website.

We may also use web beacons (also called “pixel tags”) which are non-visible images that are placed in the code on our Websites and in some emails that may be sent to you. Web beacons help us measure our customers’ online behavior and improve the effectiveness of our Websites and advertising.

We use certain third-party services to collect the non-personal information discussed above and to engage in auditing, analysis, research, and reporting. These third parties may use technologies such as cookies and web beacons.

EnChroma uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses cookies to track information and help analyze how visitors or users interact with and use the Websites. The information includes, among other things, your IP address and how long you have visited the site. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Websites, compiling reports on activity for operators of the Websites and providing other services relating to activity on the Websites and internet usage. To read Google Analytics security and privacy principles, please [click here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en). You may choose not to have data reported by Google Analytics by installing the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-analytics-opt-out/fllaojicojecljbmefodhfapmkghcbnh?hl=en).

Our Websites may also use third-party services to optimize our website by measuring how visitors interact with our website, such as Optimizely and HotJar. You can opt-out from HotJar by visiting <https://www.hotjar.com/opt-out> and for Optimizely at <https://www.optimizely.com/legal/opt-out/>.

Our Websites may also use other third-party services, such as Google AdWords and Facebook remarketing services, to advertise on third party websites to previous visitors to our Websites. Third-party vendors, including Google and Facebook, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to our Websites. Any data collected will be used in accordance with EnChroma’s own privacy policy, as well as the privacy policies of Google and Facebook. You can opt-out of remarketing by visiting the links below:

For Google: <https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en>[  
](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)For Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/>

Our Websites may also use third-party payment providers, such as Amazon Pay and PayPal, which enable you to purchase goods and services from EnChroma using your Amazon or PayPal user account. When you use a third-party payment provider, your payment information is managed by the third-party. You can learn more about the privacy policy and terms of service of Amazon Payments at <https://pay.amazon.com/>. You can learn more about the privacy policy and terms of service of PayPal at [https://www.paypal.com](https://www.paypal.com/).

## **How does EnChroma Respond to “Do Not Track” Signals?**

Some web browsers may transmit “do not track” signals to the websites and other online services with which the browser communicates.. For now, we do not take action in response to these signals. By visiting our Websites, you consent to our placement of cookies and other similar technologies on your computer and/or mobile device.

## **How does EnChroma use my information?**

We use the information we collect from you for the following purposes:

  * To provide you with information, products, or services that you request from us;
  * To respond to inquiries you submit through our Websites;
  * To present our Websites and their contents to you;
  * To communicate with you via email, mail, and by other methods of communications about EnChroma’s services, products and other EnChroma business matters;
  * To improve our services to you and improve the quality of your experience with our Websites;
  * To carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and us, including billing and collection;
  * To provide advertisements to you on our Websites and other websites about EnChroma products and services based on your browsing preferences;
  * To analyze and determine trends and statistics;
  * To fulfill any other purpose for which you provide it;
  * In any other way we may describe when you provide the information;
  * For any other purpose with your consent.

We may also use your information to contact you about our own products and services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to use your information in this way, please see section below titled “ **What choices do I have with regard to my information?”**

## **Will my information be shared?**

Your personally identifiable information may be handled by our employees, contractors, service providers, and consultants for the purpose of providing the EnChroma products or services. We may share your information with trusted partners or third-party service providers to help perform statistical analysis, send you e-mail or postal mail, provide customer service, arrange deliveries, or contact you about EnChroma products or services that may be of interest to you.

Except as described in this policy, we do not disclose personally identifiable information about you to third parties for their independent use unless: (1) you request or authorize us to do so; (2) we are required to do so in order to comply with the law (for example, to comply with a subpoena, court order); (3) we are required to do so in order to protect our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of others; (4) we are required to do so in order to address emergencies or acts of God; (5) as necessary to address disputes or claims; or (6) to a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, restructuring, reorganization, divestiture, or other sale or transfer of part or all of EnChroma’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information that EnChroma holds is among the assets transferred.

## **Third-Party Services**

Please note that this privacy policy only addresses EnChroma’s use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information. Please be aware that our Websites may contain links to other third-party websites and some content or applications on our Websites are served by third parties. EnChroma is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other websites, and EnChroma is not liable for third-party conduct with respect to personally identifiable information. You may wish to carefully read the privacy policy of such websites or services.

## **Crowdfunding Services**

EnChroma’s Websites may provide a link to a third party crowdfunding services such as, FundRazr. The FundRazr service is provided by ConnectionPoint Systems, Inc. (“CSPI”), a Canada corporation.  The personal information you provide to create a FundRazr campaign is collected and managed by CSPI. The privacy policy of CSPI for the FundRazr service is available at <https://fundrazr.com/privacy-policy>.

## **Your California Privacy Rights**

Residents of California may request certain information about our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To obtain such information, you may send an email to california-privacy@enchroma.com or a written letter via First-Class U.S. Mail addressed to:

EnChroma, Inc.  
Attention: California Privacy  
2629 7th Street  
Berkeley, CA 94710

In all such requests, please reference “California Privacy Rights Request for Third Party Information” in your letter and include your full name, street address, city, state and zip code. When contacting us by email, please include in the subject line, “California Request for Removal of Content.”  We will not accept requests via telephone or facsimile or those that do not provide complete information.

Under California law, California residents who are registered users of the Websites and are under the age of 18 are entitled to request and obtain removal of content and information that the users themselves post on the Websites.

Your letter or email should include your first and last name, registered username or login name as registered on our Website, your year of birth, your contact information, and the content that you posted on the Websites that you are requesting to be removed. Please note that your request does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information subject to your request.

## **How will EnChroma protect my information?**

To help protect your privacy and secure your personally identifiable information, EnChroma maintains reasonable physical, technical and administrative safeguards.  The security of your information also depends on you.  If the Websites you are using requires a password, please keep your password confidential and do not share it with anyone.  Maintaining the confidentiality of your password is your responsibility.  We also recommend that you change your passwords to the Websites frequently.

We restrict access to your personally identifiable information to those who need to know that information in order for us to provide products or services to you. In addition, we train our employees about the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information. We commit to taking appropriate disciplinary measures to enforce our employees’ responsibilities to protect your privacy and personally identifiable information.

When certain sensitive personal information is transmitted to certain areas of our Websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol. The use of encryption protects transmitted data from unauthorized access by third parties as it travels across the internet between your device and our Website. The ecommerce checkout process on our Website, located at <https://enchroma.com/checkout> uses SSL encryption. You can verify the security of the SSL connection by visiting the checkout page and checking the page properties in your device’s internet browser – sometimes this may appear as a green “closed lock” icon. For more information please consult the help systems for your device or browser software.

Please note that despite our efforts and commitment to keep data secure, we cannot guarantee that data transmitted over the Internet or any other public network is 100% secure. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures on the Websites. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk.

## **What choices do I have with regard to my information?**

**Email Communications**

You may opt-out of receiving marketing-related email communications from EnChroma by visiting the following webpage: <http://enchroma.com/unsubscribe>.

**Updating or Correcting Personal Information**

If you have registered with our Website, you may review and correct or update your personal information by visiting the page <http://enchroma.com/my-account>. If you do not have an account and need to check the status or correct personal information, please contact our customer service by email at [support@enchroma.com](mailto:support@enchroma.com), or call our customer service number at (510) 497-0048, or use the chat functionality which may be available during business hours on our Website. We may not accommodate all requests, for example, requests to change information that may violate any law or legal requirement or cause the information to be incorrect. We may need to verify your identity, and in some circumstances, we may need to verify the accuracy of certain information by requesting supporting documentation. You are required to provide us with accurate and complete information, and otherwise update and maintain the accuracy and completeness of that information.

**What if there are changes to this Privacy Policy or if I have questions about it?**

We may update our privacy policy from time to time. If we make material changes to this privacy policy, we will notify you by posting the changes on our Websites. Please check this privacy policy from time to time because by visiting our Websites, you agree to accept any changes to our privacy policy.

If you have any questions about our privacy policy or practices, please contact us by calling (510) 497-0048, by emailing [support@enchroma.com](mailto:support@enchroma.com), or by writing to us at:

EnChroma, Inc.  
Attention:  Privacy  
2629 7th Street  
Berkeley, CA, USA

Last modified and effective date: March 16th 2018

Copyright 2018 EnChroma, Inc. All Rights Reserved
